Finding Aid for the Alfred Newman Collection PASC-M.0019
UCLA Library Special Collections
Alfred Newman collection
circa1940-1959
UCLA Library Special Collections
Newman, Alfred
PASC-M.0019
3 Linear Feet (6 boxes)
Collection consists of 78 rpm and 33 rpm recordings of soundtracks composed by Newman, and other music conducted by Newman.
Restrictions on Access
Stored off-site. All requests to access special collections material must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9924703613606533
Biographical Note
Newman was born on Mar. 17, 1901 in New Haven, CT; became pianist, composer, and conductor; studied with Sigismond Stojowski, Reuben Goldmark, George Wedge, and Arnold Schoenberg; at age 13 he played piano at the Strand Theatre in NY, and was a pianist, accompanist, and conductor in vaudeville, and later in Broadway musicals; moved to Hollywood in 1930; appeared as a guest conductor with the Cincinnati Symphony, National Symphony, Los Angeles Philharmonic, and the Hollywood Bowl Symphony; became writer of film scores; won Academy Awards for The song of Bernadette (1943), Mother wore tights (1947), With a song in my heart (1952), Call me madam (1953), Love is a many-splendored thing (1955), The King and I (1956), and Camelot (1967); he died on Feb. 17, 1970 in Los Angeles.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of 78 rpm and 33 rpm recordings of soundtracks composed by Newman, and other music conducted by Newman.
- Alfred Newman Conducts (Box 1)
- Beloved Enemy (Box 1)
- The Bluebird, 1940 (Box 1)
- Centennial Summer (Box 2)
- Coney Island (Box 2)
- David and Bathsheba, 1951 (Box 2)
- Diamond Horshoe (Box 2)
- Dolly Sisters (Box 2)
- Dragonwyck, 1946 (Box 3)
- Gangs All Here (Box 3)
- Hello Frisco (Box 3)
- How Green Was My Valley, 1941 (Box 3)
  General note
  2 copies
- Hurricane (Box 3)
- Jitterbug (Box 4)
- Keys of the Kingdom (Box 4)
- Kitten of the Keys (Box 4)
- Leave Her to Heaven, 1945 (Box 4)
- Marco Polo, 1938 (Box 4)
- Original Themes (Box 4)
  Volume one.
- Original Themes (Box 5)
  volume 2.
- Out of This World (Box 5)
- Romeo and Juliet (Box 5)
- Schocking Miss Pilgrim (Box 5)
- Screen Guild Show 1 & 2 (Box 5)
- Song of Bernadette, 1943 (Box 5)
  Scope and Contents note
  1-4
- Song of Bernadette, 1943 (Box 6)
  5-8
- Stella Dallas (Box 6)
- They Shall Have Music, 1939 (Box 6)
- Where Do We Go From Here (Box 6)
- Wuthering Heights, 1939 (Box 6)